Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning the U.S. Motion Picture Industry
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning the U.S. motion picture industry
1916-1948
Ndy98 T4
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2
(5 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning the U.S. motion picture industry. Examples of these documents include reports, prospectuses, analyses, press releases, clippings of newspaper articles, advertisements, business plans, company profiles, letters and notices to the stockholders, stockholder agreements, proxy statements, subscription agreements, new stock issues, listing bulletins, bond offerings, trust deeds, mortgage indentures, and readjustment plans. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning the U.S. motion picture industry. Examples of these documents include reports, prospectuses, analyses, press releases, clippings of newspaper articles, advertisements, business plans, company profiles, letters and notices to the stockholders, stockholder agreements, proxy statements, subscription agreements, new stock issues, listing bulletins, bond offerings, trust deeds, mortgage indentures, and readjustment plans. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Motion picture industry -- United States; Motion picture studios -- United States; Proxy statements -- Specimens.; Trust indentures -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Alexander Industries, 1928; Ndy98 T4 AL27; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Columbia Pictures Corporation, 1935; Ndy98 T4 +C723; (1 document) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Eastman Teaching Films, Inc., 1928; Ndy98 T4 Ea79; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Famous Players Canadian Corporation, Limited, 1928; Ndy98 T4 +F19; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- First National Pictures, Inc., 1925; Ndy98 T4 +F51; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- First National Properties, Inc., 1926; Ndy98 T4 +F52; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fox West Coast Theatres, 1930; Ndy98 T4 +F836; (1 document) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- General Theatres Equipment, Inc., 1930-1939; Ndy98 T4 +G28; (7 documents) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Goldwyn Pictures Corporation, 1924; Ndy98 T4 +G581; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Grand Rapids Operating Corporation, 1926; Ndy98 T4 +G763; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- D.W. Griffith, Inc., 1920-1923; Ndy98 T4 +G875; (4 documents) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Hennepin Avenue Theatre and Realty Company, 1921; Ndy98 T4 +H39; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- B.F. Keith Corporation, 1921-1926; Ndy98 T4 +K26; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Keith Memorial Theatre Corporation, 1928; Ndy98 T4 +K266; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Loew's Boston Theatres Company, 1922; Ndy98 T4 +L824; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Loew's Incorporated, 1920-1943; Ndy98 T4 +L826; (21 documents) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Loew's Ohio Theatres, Incorporated, 1926; Ndy98 T4 +L827; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Motion Picture Capital Corporation, 1925-1926; Ndy98 T4 +M85; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- New England Theatres Operating Corporation, 1930; Ndy98 T4 +N97; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Olympia Theatres, Incorporated, 1924; Ndy98 T4 +OL9; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Orpheum Circuit Inc., 1919-1928; Ndy98 T4 +Or7; (9 documents) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Paramount Pictures Inc., 1919-1948; Ndy98 T4 +P214; (41 documents) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  Scope and Contents
  Included are documents from the Famous Players-Lasky Corporation, the Paramount Famous Lasky Corporation and the Paramount-Publix Corporation.
- Paramount Properties Incorporated, 1927; Ndy98 T4 +P216; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Pathe Exchange, Inc., 1921-1934; Ndy98 T4 +P273; (8 documents) (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Radio-Keith-Orpheum Corporation, 1928-1944; Ndy98 T4 +R119; (20 documents) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Radio-Keith-Orpheum Distributing Corporation, 1934-1936; Ndy98 T4 +R13; (2 documents) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Reelcraft Pictures Corporation, 1920; Ndy98 T4 +R257; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Stanley Company of America, 1927; Ndy98 T4 +St2; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Stanley-Mark-Strand Corporation, 1926; Ndy98 T4 +St25; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Technicolor, Inc., 1923-1930; Ndy98 T4 +T22; (5 documents) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Technicolor Motion Picture Corporation, 1921-1925; Ndy98 T4 +T23; (5 documents) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Trans-Lux Daylight Picture Screen Corporation, 1926-1934; Ndy98 T4 +T687; (3 documents) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation, 1928-1943; Ndy98 T4 +T918; (12 documents) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- United Artists Theatre Circuit, Inc., 1926-1927; Ndy98 T4 +Un213; (2 documents) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- United Picture Productions Corporation, 1919; Ndy98 T4 +Un3; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Universal Corporation, 1936; Ndy98 T4 +Un31; (4 documents) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Universal Pictures Company, 1927-1940; Ndy98 T4 +Un35; (4 documents) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Vitagraph Company of America, 1916; Ndy98 T4 +V831; (1 document) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Warner Bros. Pictures, Inc., 1925-1943; Ndy98 T4 +W24; (21 documents) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Wilmer and Vincent Corporation, 1926; Ndy98 T4 +W68; (1 document) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- World Film Corporation, 1919; Ndy98 T4 +W893; (2 documents) (Box 4, Folder 5)